<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>The Djakartan Dispatch</title>
  <subtitle></subtitle>
  <link href="https://dispatch.jakarta.dj/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://dispatch.jakarta.dj/"/>
  
    <updated>2023-02-28T00:00:00Z</updated>
  
  <id>https://dispatch.jakarta.dj</id>
  <author>
    <name>Author Name</name>
    <email>author@site.com</email>
  </author>
  
    
    <entry>
      <title>Introduction Post</title>
      <link href="https://dispatch.jakarta.dj/posts/introduction-post/"/>
      <updated>2022-09-10T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <id>https://dispatch.jakarta.dj/posts/introduction-post/</id>
      <content type="html">
        <![CDATA[
      <blockquote>
<p>Jakarta o' Jakarta, how I love to hate you.</p>
</blockquote>
<h2>Salam Kenal!</h2>
<p><img src="https://dispatch.jakarta.dj/images/posts/bundaran-hi.png" alt="Image of Jakarta's Bundaran HI, Monas"></p>
<p>Hello, my name is Dania Rifki, I'm a native of Jakarta, Indonesia, and this is where I will put all my writings about Jakarta on. <a href="https://youtu.be/fIZ9c585kf4">You may remember me from that one video about Jakarta's Public Transportation</a>, this website acts as a spiritual successor to that video. I was originally going to continue <em>Developing Jakarta</em>, but it had a few hurdles.</p>
<p>First, I don't have much time nor money to produce a complete polished video like <em>Developing Jakarta</em> often. I was lucky that I was able to make it at all, but it just wasn't really sustainable if I do more of it. Plus, Text allows me to publish faster, make corrections easier and to reword sections if I saw fit.</p>
<p>Second, I don't really enjoy being on camera, I'm a transgender woman, and being on camera is really stressful for me; I'm also not that good of a presenter compared to someone like Jay Foreman.</p>
<p>Third, Text allows me to be more personal. You'll notice that I tried shoehorning jokes to the first episode of <em>Developing Jakarta</em>, while I never intended it to be popular, it was done so YouTube doesn't bury the video too much. I felt like my direction is controlled by YouTube implicitly; I much rather have a more independent publication that I can count on.</p>
<p>Fourth, Developing Jakarta was focused on city planning. I want to also talk about the city's history, politics, et cetera. However, YouTube's coverage of those genres are incredibly toxic and/or require censoring.</p>
<p>These, along with more smaller reasons are why I started <strong>The Djakartan Dispatch</strong> as an independent website.</p>
<h2>What will <em>The Dispatch</em> cover?</h2>
<p>Mainly about topics related to the Jakarta Metropolitan Area (Jabodetabek) and Indonesia. This includes, but not limited to: city planning, transportation discussions, housing projects, local history, and current events surrounding the city. I will also talk about Indonesia-wide topics when I feel there's something worth saying about, perhaps I will cover international topics (i.e. Developments in Singapore or San Francisco) at times.</p>
<p><em>The Dispatch</em> will not have a consistent schedule, I will only be writing articles when I feel there is a need to, it is also independent and has no funding, although I hope to start a tip jar in the near future (perhaps something like Ko-Fi).</p>
<h2>In Closing</h2>
<p>Thank you for taking the time to read the introduction of <strong>The Djakartan Dispatch</strong>, I hope you will continue to support us in the future, cheers!</p>
<p>Endnote: Feel free to contact the dispatch on thedjakartandispatch <code>at</code> protonmail <code>dot</code> com. We love getting feedback, we also accept guest post submissions!</p>
<p>- Dania Rifki</p>

    ]]>
      </content>
    </entry>
  
    
    <entry>
      <title>The Governor of Jakarta: The Legacy of Ali Sadikin</title>
      <link href="https://dispatch.jakarta.dj/posts/the-legacy-of-ali-sadikin/"/>
      <updated>2022-11-14T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <id>https://dispatch.jakarta.dj/posts/the-legacy-of-ali-sadikin/</id>
      <content type="html">
        <![CDATA[
      <blockquote>
<p>Jakarta must be free from aversion and become a common city for the rich and poor regardless of race and ethnicity.
- Ali Sadikin</p>
</blockquote>
<p><img src="https://dispatch.jakarta.dj/images/posts/ali-sadikin.png" alt="Plotted image of Ali Sadikin"></p>
<p>The following is a brief article about Ali Sadikin, I originally wanted to write more, but I realized that it would be inappropriate for a general overview of him to include.</p>
<p>Ali Sadikin is one person not commonly known or talked about outside of Indonesia. He was the Fourth Governor of Jakarta during the Suharto Dictatorship, and he's widely known here as probably the most influential governor in the History of Jakarta. Ali had positions in power before becoming Governor, but I want to focus on his governorship, as that's what most people know him for.</p>
<p>If you want to know one thing about Ali, He was ruthlessly pragmatic. Legalizing gambling and prostitution to fund education and other public services. He was liberal enough to sign the Petition of Fifty, an anti-government document, and was nominated as an alternative president by Students during a protest. Yet authoritarian enough to forcibly clear out slums, ban <em>becaks</em> (cycle rickshaws), and outlaw street peddlers.</p>
<p>He supported unpopular policies like family planning, which was eventually accepted in the mainstream, and support for Waria (A form of Third Gender), which wasn't very accepted at all. Ali famously attended the wedding of Indonesia's first trans woman legally recognized as her true gender, Vivian Rubiyanti Iskandar.</p>
<p>Most people remember him today for Infrastructure and Transportation. Ali oversaw the construction and inauguration of Ismail Marzuki Park, Ancol Dreamland, and even the revitalization of Senen. He laid the groundwork for the modern Jakartan Public Transit system, and motor vehicle usage exploded during his tenure.</p>
<p>Ali Sadikin was eventually removed from power on July 5, 1977, after having allegedly &quot;allowed&quot; Golkar to lose an election in Jakarta and later became the chairman of the Indonesian Football Association. On May 20, 2008, he passed away in Singapore and was buried in Tanah Kusir Cemetery in Jakarta the following day, as was his wish.</p>
<h2>My Opinion of Ali Sadikin</h2>
<p>Ali Sadikin was someone who I as an Indonesian Liberal have had a complex relationship with. He, like Lee Kuan Yew of Singapore, transformed Jakarta from an impoverished post-colonial mess to the start of the mega metropolis that you see today with an iron fist. At the same time, his authoritarianism was more pragmatic than the more totalitarian bent you see with Suharto.</p>
<p>I'd even go as far as to argue that Ali, not Suharto is the LKY of Indonesia. Ali and LKY both are fiscally pragmatic, authoritarian-leaning leaders who led their citizens to prosperity. Suharto was a corrupt militarist who embezzled a lot of money from international organizations, and I'd argue he wasn't that good of a leader, to begin with.</p>
<p>I hope this article sparks more interest in reading about Bang Ali. I recommend Tirto's Articles on him (Google Translate should be accurate enough for Indonesian), and the English Wikipedia page to start. Thank you for reading.</p>
<h2>Sources and Further Reading</h2>
<p>Tirto:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://tirto.id/anak-betawi-ketemu-bang-ali-sadikin-fQ8x">https://tirto.id/anak-betawi-ketemu-bang-ali-sadikin-fQ8x</a></li>
<li><a href="https://tirto.id/jejak-ali-sadikin-mendukung-program-kb-hingga-berskala-nasional-f71L">https://tirto.id/jejak-ali-sadikin-mendukung-program-kb-hingga-berskala-nasional-f71L</a></li>
<li><a href="https://tirto.id/bagaimana-ali-sadikin-mencari-solusi-untuk-kemaksiatan-jakarta-czlE">https://tirto.id/bagaimana-ali-sadikin-mencari-solusi-untuk-kemaksiatan-jakarta-czlE</a></li>
<li><a href="https://tirto.id/sebelum-mrt-sejarah-rekayasa-transportasi-massal-ala-ali-sadikin-dlyw">https://tirto.id/sebelum-mrt-sejarah-rekayasa-transportasi-massal-ala-ali-sadikin-dlyw</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Wikipedia (Yes, I am lazily linking the page here instead of the references):</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ali_Sadikin">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ali_Sadikin</a></li>
</ul>
<h2>In Closing</h2>
<p>Thank you for taking the time to read <strong>The Djakartan Dispatch</strong>, I hope you will continue to support us in the future, cheers!</p>
<p>Endnote: Feel free to contact the dispatch on thedjakartandispatch <code>at</code> protonmail <code>dot</code> com. We love getting feedback, we also accept guest post submissions!</p>
<p>- Dania Rifki</p>

    ]]>
      </content>
    </entry>
  
    
    <entry>
      <title>Urbanism for Realists</title>
      <link href="https://dispatch.jakarta.dj/posts/urbanism-for-realists/"/>
      <updated>2023-02-28T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <id>https://dispatch.jakarta.dj/posts/urbanism-for-realists/</id>
      <content type="html">
        <![CDATA[
      <blockquote>
<p>&quot;Amsterdam wasn't built in a day.&quot; - David Hamilton</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Anyone who has spent the last three years online, knows about the amazing rise in Urbanism content online. From the top dogs NotJustBikes and Adam Something to more obscure content creators like <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@OhTheUrbanity">Oh The Urbanity!</a> and <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@PaigeMTL">Paige Saunders</a>. This is all good, I'm glad to see more advocacy for people-centric Urbanism online. However, I feel like a dark undertone had taken over some Urbanist spaces, that being the &quot;Urban Idealists&quot;.</p>
<p>The Urban Idealist believes that their silver bullet ideas would transform cities into Utopia, regardless of the pre-existing socioeconomic conditions. To them, we can easily disregard a city’s culture, transport methods, climate, geography. All cities can be exactly like Amsterdam or Barcelona. While it is true that some of the NIMBY “complaints” raise these points, dismissing them outright is not a good response.</p>
<h2>Be Pragmatic</h2>
<p>What works in city 𝑥 may not work in 𝑦. Ignoring the existing city design, both in its infrastructure and culture, may result in ineffective reforms and redesigns happening. Take my home city of Jakarta. Like American cities, we have Cars and Stroads which were built from bulldozing old buildings and Tram Infrastructure, but unlike most American cities. We have the Angkot or Microbus that lower income Jakartans take. In fact, it’s so successful that a version of Angkots (Called Mikrotrans) are officially part of Jakarta’s official system nowadays! <a href="https://www.kompas.com/tren/read/2022/02/02/103000765/mengenal-mikrotrans-angkot-ber-ac-di-jakarta-dengan-segudang-fasilitas?page=all">1</a></p>
<p><img src="https://dispatch.jakarta.dj/images/posts/urbanism-for-realists/angkot.jpeg" alt="Image of a Jak Lingko Angkot"></p>
<p>But now time to turn into what we do worse than US Cities, Jakarta has Mopeds, a lot of Mopeds. And the riders of those mopeds are the craziest people on the road! They not only flagrantly ignore stop lights when the opportunity arises, but they’ll ride on the separated Bike Lane or even the god-damn Pavement! <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/uk-indonesia-pavements/jakartans-walk-the-walk-to-regain-their-pavement-idUSLNE83102120120402">2</a></p>
<p><img src="https://dispatch.jakarta.dj/images/posts/urbanism-for-realists/mopeds-on-pavement.jpg" alt="Image of Mopeds on a Pavement disturbing pedestrians"></p>
<p>Clearly, this means that regular Dutch urban policies will not necessarily work, and if we were to import them, we will have to figure out how to adapt them to local conditions. Urbanists shouldn't advocate mass replanning of everything immediately, but rather go through it step by step to minimize backlash. And tune city planning policies to how people react to those changes in urban design. Similar to the RCTs being used in Development Economics <a href="https://theconversation.com/how-randomised-trials-became-big-in-development-economics-128398">3</a>.</p>
<p>Which brings me to…</p>
<h2>Yes, Culture Matters</h2>
<p>Amsterdam and other Dutch cities are successful not only due to their excellent infrastructure, but also their culture. It is fair to avoid discussions of culture in transport policymaking to avoid distractions from more core issues, but, as Alex Davis writes in his video essay about his visit to the Netherlands <a href="https://youtu.be/UB8HI_luyRU?t=281">4</a>. Even though Giethoorn (A village famous for being car-free and usage of boats)’s bus service is by most measures, awful, people still use it often due to the Dutch cultural expectation that transit is the way to travel long distances.</p>
<p>Davis then goes to examples of subpar unprotected bike infrastructure, yet argues that they are still safer than protected bike lanes in the US because of the cultural expectation that you respect bicycle infrastructure.</p>
<p>Despite the gloomy attitude this section gives, there are ways to influence change in culture through policymaking. Davis gives the examples of giving schoolchildren free transit passes, or increasing bicycle use by incentivising small deliveries to be done by cargo bikes.</p>
<p>One interesting example is Rio de Janeiro. People used to not care about drink-driving, until there was a mass campaign in the mid-2000s to eradicate the practice, it was a mix of advertisements and heavy enforcement by the police. Now, most people in Rio wouldn't consider drinking and driving, even if they're in a part of Brazil where consequences for drink-driving aren’t enforced. (Thanks to Décarte for pointing this out).</p>
<h2>Hit close to home</h2>
<p>Amsterdam, as it is now, was not built in a day. It was being redesigned for the car when they got cheap in the 60s, until the 70s, when traffic deaths were as high as 9 people dying each day. People started protesting to demand better cycling policies, the most notable of this was the <em>Stop de Kindermoord</em> (EN: Stop the Children Slaughter) Movement, policymakers were moved, and notable experiments to improve cycling safety were done. Those experiments eventually became the standard-bearer for cycle lanes in the Netherlands <a href="https://youtu.be/SYHz93HXJFQ">5</a>.</p>
<p>I feel like from the example of Amsterdam, Urbanist campaigners should focus on sending messages that resonate with the local community rather than more detached concepts. “Solving Climate Change” is nice, but “Make Kids Safe in our Area” is better.</p>
<h2>Big-Tent Coalition</h2>
<p>The sister movement of the Urbanists is the YIMBY movement, and I’d say Urbanists have a lot to learn from them. One notable thing is they are Big-Tent movements with a defined focus. They transcend ideology, you’ll find socialists, liberals, libertarians, conservatives, etc in one room <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20210521051949/https://exponentsmag.org/2021/05/20/against-activist-mission-creep">6</a>. The urbanist movement, on the other hand, seems more slanted and less of a big-tent which risks of it being the centre of the culture war (Yes I am aware that it partially already is <a href="https://youtu.be/7z8Tb7OA_F4">7</a>, but it’s not in the spotlight unlike, sadly, Transgender Rights).</p>
<p>In his book <em>Of Boys and Men</em>, Richard V. Reeves writes how cultural warfare and wedge issues lead to pointless bickering and failure to address real issues <a href="https://www.brookings.edu/book/of-boys-and-men">8</a>. I fear that may happen to Urbanism.</p>
<h2>In Closing</h2>
<p>I would like to give thanks to Décarte from Alon Levy's Discord Server and u/brinvestor for the feedback of this article's first draft.</p>
<p>Thank you for taking the time to read <strong>The Djakartan Dispatch</strong>, I hope you will continue to support us in the future, cheers!</p>
<p>Endnote: Feel free to contact the dispatch on thedjakartandispatch <code>at</code> protonmail <code>dot</code> com. We love getting feedback, we also accept guest post submissions!</p>
<p>- Dania Rifki</p>

    ]]>
      </content>
    </entry>
  
</feed>