<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>The Djakartan Dispatch</title>
  <subtitle></subtitle>
  <link href="https://dispatch.jakarta.dj/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://dispatch.jakarta.dj/"/>
  
    <updated>2022-11-14T00:00:00Z</updated>
  
  <id>https://dispatch.jakarta.dj</id>
  <author>
    <name>Author Name</name>
    <email>author@site.com</email>
  </author>
  
    
    <entry>
      <title>Introduction Post</title>
      <link href="https://dispatch.jakarta.dj/posts/introduction-post/"/>
      <updated>2022-09-10T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <id>https://dispatch.jakarta.dj/posts/introduction-post/</id>
      <content type="html">
        <![CDATA[
      <blockquote>
<p>Jakarta o' Jakarta, how I love to hate you.</p>
</blockquote>
<h2>Salam Kenal!</h2>
<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/7U3dFjv.png" alt="Image of Jakarta's Bundaran HI, Monas"></p>
<p>Hello, my name is Dania Rifki, I'm a native of Jakarta, Indonesia, and this is where I will put all my writings about Jakarta on. <a href="https://youtu.be/fIZ9c585kf4">You may remember me from that one video about Jakarta's Public Transportation</a>, this website acts as a spiritual successor to that video. I was originally going to continue <em>Developing Jakarta</em>, but it had a few hurdles.</p>
<p>First, I don't have much time nor money to produce a complete polished video like <em>Developing Jakarta</em> often. I was lucky that I was able to make it at all, but it just wasn't really sustainable if I do more of it. Plus, Text allows me to publish faster, make corrections easier and to reword sections if I saw fit.</p>
<p>Second, I don't really enjoy being on camera, I'm a transgender woman, and being on camera is really stressful for me; I'm also not that good of a presenter compared to someone like Jay Foreman.</p>
<p>Third, Text allows me to be more personal. You'll notice that I tried shoehorning jokes to the first episode of <em>Developing Jakarta</em>, while I never intended it to be popular, it was done so YouTube doesn't bury the video too much. I felt like my direction is controlled by YouTube implicitly; I much rather have a more independent publication that I can count on.</p>
<p>Fourth, Developing Jakarta was focused on city planning. I want to also talk about the city's history, politics, et cetera. However, YouTube's coverage of those genres are incredibly toxic and/or require censoring.</p>
<p>These, along with more smaller reasons are why I started <strong>The Djakartan Dispatch</strong> as an independent website.</p>
<h2>What will <em>The Dispatch</em> cover?</h2>
<p>Mainly about topics related to the Jakarta Metropolitan Area (Jabodetabek) and Indonesia. This includes, but not limited to: city planning, transportation discussions, housing projects, local history, and current events surrounding the city. I will also talk about Indonesia-wide topics when I feel there's something worth saying about, perhaps I will cover international topics (i.e. Developments in Singapore or San Francisco) at times.</p>
<p><em>The Dispatch</em> will not have a consistent schedule, I will only be writing articles when I feel there is a need to, it is also independent and has no funding, although I hope to start a tip jar in the near future (perhaps something like Ko-Fi).</p>
<h2>In Closing</h2>
<p>Thank you for taking the time to read the introduction of <strong>The Djakartan Dispatch</strong>, I hope you will continue to support us in the future, cheers!</p>
<p>Endnote: Feel free to contact the dispatch on thedjakartandispatch <code>at</code> protonmail <code>dot</code> com. We love getting feedback, we also accept guest post submissions!</p>
<p>- Dania Rifki</p>

    ]]>
      </content>
    </entry>
  
    
    <entry>
      <title>The Governor of Jakarta - The Legacy of Ali Sadikin</title>
      <link href="https://dispatch.jakarta.dj/posts/the-governor-of-jakarta-the-legacy-of-ali-sadikin/"/>
      <updated>2022-11-14T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <id>https://dispatch.jakarta.dj/posts/the-governor-of-jakarta-the-legacy-of-ali-sadikin/</id>
      <content type="html">
        <![CDATA[
      <blockquote>
<p>Jakarta must be free from aversion and become a common city for the rich and poor regardless of race and ethnicity.
- Ali Sadikin</p>
</blockquote>
<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/vIuFL3e.png" alt="Plotted image of Ali Sadikin"></p>
<p>The following is a brief article about Ali Sadikin, I originally wanted to write more, but I realized that it would be inappropriate for a general overview of him to include.</p>
<p>Ali Sadikin is one person not commonly known or talked about outside of Indonesia. He was the Fourth Governor of Jakarta during the Suharto Dictatorship, and he's widely known here as probably the most influential governor in the History of Jakarta. Ali had positions in power before becoming Governor, but I want to focus on his governorship, as that's what most people know him for.</p>
<p>If you want to know one thing about Ali, He was ruthlessly pragmatic. Legalizing gambling and prostitution to fund education and other public services. He was liberal enough to sign the Petition of Fifty, an anti-government document, and was nominated as an alternative president by Students during a protest. Yet authoritarian enough to forcibly clear out slums, ban <em>becaks</em> (cycle rickshaws), and outlaw street peddlers.</p>
<p>He supported unpopular policies like family planning, which was eventually accepted in the mainstream, and support for Waria (A form of Third Gender), which wasn't very accepted at all. Ali famously attended the wedding of Indonesia's first trans woman legally recognized as her true gender, Vivian Rubiyanti Iskandar.</p>
<p>Most people remember him today for Infrastructure and Transportation. Ali oversaw the construction and inauguration of Ismail Marzuki Park, Ancol Dreamland, and even the revitalization of Senen. He laid the groundwork for the modern Jakartan Public Transit system, and motor vehicle usage exploded during his tenure.</p>
<p>Ali Sadikin was eventually removed from power on July 5, 1977, after having allegedly &quot;allowed&quot; Golkar to lose an election in Jakarta and later became the chairman of the Indonesian Football Association. On May 20, 2008, he passed away in Singapore and was buried in Tanah Kusir Cemetery in Jakarta the following day, as was his wish.</p>
<h2>My Opinion of Ali Sadikin</h2>
<p>Ali Sadikin was someone who I as an Indonesian Liberal have had a complex relationship with. He, like Lee Kuan Yew of Singapore, transformed Jakarta from an impoverished post-colonial mess to the start of the mega metropolis that you see today with an iron fist. At the same time, his authoritarianism was more pragmatic than the more totalitarian bent you see with Suharto.</p>
<p>I'd even go as far as to argue that Ali, not Suharto is the LKY of Indonesia. Ali and LKY both are fiscally pragmatic, authoritarian-leaning leaders who led their citizens to prosperity. Suharto was a corrupt militarist who embezzled a lot of money from international organizations, and I'd argue he wasn't that good of a leader, to begin with.</p>
<p>I hope this article sparks more interest in reading about Bang Ali. I recommend Tirto's Articles on him (Google Translate should be accurate enough for Indonesian), and the English Wikipedia page to start. Thank you for reading.</p>
<h2>Sources and Further Reading</h2>
<p>Tirto:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://tirto.id/anak-betawi-ketemu-bang-ali-sadikin-fQ8x">https://tirto.id/anak-betawi-ketemu-bang-ali-sadikin-fQ8x</a></li>
<li><a href="https://tirto.id/jejak-ali-sadikin-mendukung-program-kb-hingga-berskala-nasional-f71L">https://tirto.id/jejak-ali-sadikin-mendukung-program-kb-hingga-berskala-nasional-f71L</a></li>
<li><a href="https://tirto.id/bagaimana-ali-sadikin-mencari-solusi-untuk-kemaksiatan-jakarta-czlE">https://tirto.id/bagaimana-ali-sadikin-mencari-solusi-untuk-kemaksiatan-jakarta-czlE</a></li>
<li><a href="https://tirto.id/sebelum-mrt-sejarah-rekayasa-transportasi-massal-ala-ali-sadikin-dlyw">https://tirto.id/sebelum-mrt-sejarah-rekayasa-transportasi-massal-ala-ali-sadikin-dlyw</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Wikipedia (Yes, I am lazily linking the page here instead of the references):</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ali_Sadikin">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ali_Sadikin</a></li>
</ul>
<h2>In Closing</h2>
<p>Thank you for taking the time to read <strong>The Djakartan Dispatch</strong>, I hope you will continue to support us in the future, cheers!</p>
<p>Endnote: Feel free to contact the dispatch on thedjakartandispatch <code>at</code> protonmail <code>dot</code> com. We love getting feedback, we also accept guest post submissions!</p>
<p>- Dania Rifki</p>

    ]]>
      </content>
    </entry>
  
</feed>